# Ning Gao

(+49) 1522 2441871 Stuttgart, Germany

**Doctoral Researcher** 

ning.gao@de.bosch.com gaobaoding.github.io

2020

I'm a fourth-year PhD student in Autonomous Learning Robots (ALR) at KIT supervised by Prof. Gerhard Neumann. I'm also a doctoral researcher at Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence (BCAI), Renningen, Germany. My research interests lie in the field of meta-learning and self-supervised learning on Robot Perception & Manipulation, e.g. robotic grasping, 6D object pose estimation and unseen object segmentation.

## **SKILLS**

LanguagesPython, Bash, 上下上X, MarkDownToolsGit, ROS, Blender, Pytorch, Open3DCommunicationChinese (native), English, German

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Researcher
Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence
Renningen, Germany
Meta-Learning, Representation Learning, Robot Manipulation

Master Thesis StudentMay 2019 — Oct 2019Bosch Center for Artificial IntelligenceRenningen, GermanyBenchmarking deep learning algorithms for 6DoF object pose estimation

Research Intern

Bosch Corporate Research

Driver's gaze estimation for autonomous driving

Oct 2018 — Feb 2019

Renningen, Germany

Research Intern

Bosch Corporate Research

Build interior camera system prototype for autonomous driving

Mar 2018 — Aug 2018

Renningen, Germany

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Institute of Measurement and Control Systems (MRT), KIT

Joint tracking for multiple pedestrians and vehicles

Nov 2017 — May 2018

Karlsruhe, Germany

Summer Intern
Daimler Greater China Ltd.
Engine testing and calibration

Jun. 2015 — Sep. 2015
Beijing, China

# **EDUCATION**

Doctoral Researcher in Computer Science2020-PresentKarlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karlsruhe, Germany2016-2019M.Sc in Mechanical Engineering2016-2019Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, Karlsruhe, Germany2011-2016B.Sc in Automotive Engineering2011-2016Tongji University, Shanghai2011-2016Outstanding Graduate Award2008-2011Daqing, Heilongjiang Province2008-2011

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Reviewer of ICRA2021, ICRA2022, IROS2022, CoRL2022, CoRL2023
The Machine Learning Summer School, Tübingen, Germany

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Meta-Learning Regrasping Strategies for Physical-Agnostic Objects	Under review ICRA 2024
Gao, Ning and Zhang, Jingyu and Chen, Ruijie and Vien, Ngo Anh and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann,	Gerhard
SA6D: Self-Adaptive Few-Shot 6D Pose Estimator for Novel and Occluded Objects	CoRL 2023
Gao, Ning and Vien, Ngo Anh and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann, Gerhard	
Enhancing Interpretable Object Abstraction via Clustering-based Slot Initialization	BMVC 2023

Gao, Ning and Hohmann, Bernard and Neumann, Gerhard

What Matters for Meta-Learning Vision Regression Tasks? CVPR 2022

Gao, Ning and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Vien, Ngo Anh and Volpp, Michael and Neumann, Gerhard

Category-Agnostic 6D Pose Estimation with Conditional Neural Processes WiCV workshop, CVPR 2022

(+49) 1522 2441871 Stuttgart, Germany

# Ning Gao Doctoral Researcher

ning.gao@de.bosch.com gaobaoding.github.io

Li, Yumeng\* and **Gao, Ning\*** and Ziesche, Hanna Carolin and Neumann, Gerhard

Signature: Datum: